<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Activities on Cubscouts Pack 499</title>
    <link>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Activities on Cubscouts Pack 499</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>STEM: Pop rocket</title>
      <link>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/stem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/stem/</guid>
      <description>The Alka-Seltzer pop rocket experiment is a fun and simple science activity that demonstrates principles of chemical reactions, gas production, and Newton&amp;rsquo;s Third Law of Motion. This experiment involves creating a small &amp;ldquo;rocket&amp;rdquo; using common household items: Alka-Seltzer tablets, water, and a film canister or similar container with a tight-fitting lid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Council</title>
      <link>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/council/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/council/</guid>
      <description>There are many activities organized at council level. SignUP and participate. SVMBC website</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Funding: Popcorn</title>
      <link>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/popcorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/popcorn/</guid>
      <description>Popcorn program is the only council sponsered money earning activity once a year allows the Scouts to raise funds to pay their own way through scouting, including summer camps, equipment, and other experience. Scout with the help of Registered Adult Partner creates an account in Trail&amp;rsquo;s End and co-ordinate with the Pack Popcorn chair to participate in the program.
Logistics for Popcorn program: Create account in Train&amp;rsquo;s End. Signup for the shifts (Max 2 per Scout) in Trail&amp;rsquo;s End.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pack Event: Raingutter Regatta</title>
      <link>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/rgr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/rgr/</guid>
      <description>Saturday, Nov 16th 2024! Register here for participating. If you have participated in voting in Den channel, this is not required.
How to prepare ? This blog is a good starting point and you may explore other resources for information that falls within the recommended BSA cubscouts standards in preparing the boat for the racing.
Racing Groups &amp;amp; Prizes LIONs/TIGERs Wolf/Bears Webelos/AoL There will be 1st, 2nd, 3rd places per group and participation recognition for each participant!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pack Event: Pinewood Derby</title>
      <link>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/pwd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sbiapack499.org/activities/pwd/</guid>
      <description>Register here[CLOSED]
About Pinewood Derby
Since it was first introduced in 1953 by Don Murphy, a Cubmaster in California, Pine Wood Derby(PWD) has become one of the most popular and favorite activity for cubscouts. It is one of the most celebrated tradition in Cubscouts. Pack499 had a blasting performance in 2022, 2023 with multiple awards in various categories. PWD is about creativity, innovation and parent/caregiver - scout collaboration span multiple weeks to build a car from a single piece of derby and compete among the cubscouts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
